<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Rabbi Ovadiah Yosef Calendar</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="zipcode">Zipcode</string>
    <string name="title_location_permission">No location permission</string>
    <string name="text_location_permission">
        Ideally, this app needs location permissions in order to accurately calculate the zmanim.
        Therefore, it is better to allow the app to see your location. We do not use your location
        for any other purpose than to calculate the zmanim.\n\n(Note: As of Android 11, the app can not
        ask you for location permissions more than once per install. You might need to re-install
        the app to use your location.) \n\nHowever, if you still do not want to give location
        permissions, you can choose to search for your address or a zipcode and the app will find your location based on your approximate area.
        (This is not recommended if you want accurate zmanim.)
    </string>

    <string name="setup_elevation">Setup Elevation</string>
    <string name="mishor_request">If you want to use Mishor (Sea Level) Sunrise/Sunset for your calculations
        of the zmanim, just press the button below:</string>
    <string name="mishor_sea_level">Mishor (Sea Level)</string>
    <string name="manual_button">If you want to specify the elevation level (in meters) yourself,
        press this button:</string>
    <string name="manual">Manual</string>
    <string name="geonames_request">If you want to get this information from GeoNames.com,
        press this button:</string>
    <string name="chaitables">ChaiTables</string>

    <string name="long_explanation">
        I have heard from Rabbi Darshan (creator of the Ohr HaChaim Luach in Israel) that Rabbi Ovadiah Yosef ZT\"L held that the actual sunrise/sunset that should be used for calculating zmanim is when sunrise/sunset is seen at the highest point in the city. However, Rabbi David Yosef Shlita writes that many have told him that Rabbi Ovadiah ZT\"L held to use Mishor (Sea Level) sunrise/sunset. Therefore, you can use the buttons below to choose the appropriate settings that you want. (See Halacha Berura vol. 14, in Otzrot Yosef (Kuntrus Ki Ba Hashemesh), Siman 6, Perek 21 for an in depth discussion)
    </string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="helper_text">Welcome to the Rabbi Ovadiah Yosef Calendar App, this app was made to help you find out the most accurate zmanim of the day according to Rabbi Ovadiah Yosef ZT\"L for your own city! There are a few things to know before using the app.

 \n\n1.) Setup elevation and visible sunrise for where you are currently located. In this first step, you should ideally choose your city and download the visible sunrise tables. Through the simple setup, the elevation data will automatically be downloaded as well. This table contains the most accurate times for VISIBLE sunrise, and this is the algorithm that the Ohr HaChaim calendar uses in Israel. However, these tables only go on for 2 years into the future and will need to be updated bi-yearly. If you do not want to use these tables, you can choose not to download them through the advanced menu, and the app will instead use the regular algorithm for sunrise (without elevation included).

 \n\n2.) There are a few different minhagim to choose from in the settings part of the app. Make sure to choose the correct ones for your city/kehila. For example, the default candle lighting time is set to 20 minutes before sunset, and the default end time for shabbat is set to 40 minutes after sunset. Please change these settings to your own customs.

 \n\n3.) Lastly, the zmanim can be included with seconds, DO NOT RELY ON THESE SECONDS. The only zman that can be relied on to the second is the visible sunrise time based on chaitables.com. Otherwise, these zmanim are NOT accurate to the second! You should always round up or down a minute or two just in case.

 \n\nIn addition to all of this, there are features in place that will automatically tell you to update the elevation data or the visible sunrise tables. If you leave the city that you currently setup the app for, the app will prompt you to run the setup again. The reason for this feature is because elevation will change based on the city that you are located in and you will have to update it every time you change cities, however, this feature will only turn on if you use elevation.
    </string>
    <string name="contact_header">Contact the developer</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>
    <string name="help">Help</string>
    <string name="search_for_a_place">Search for a place</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="full_setup">Full Setup</string>
    <string name="minhagim">Minhagim</string>
    <string name="are_you_in_israel">Are you in Israel?</string>
    <string name="i_am_in_israel">I am in Israel</string>
    <string name="i_am_not_in_israel">I am not in Israel</string>
    <string name="quick_setup">Quick Setup</string>
    <string name="advanced_setup">Advanced Setup</string>
    <string name="restart">Restart</string>
    <string name="download">Download</string>
    <string name="setup_both_elevation_and_visible_sunrise">Setup both elevation and visible sunrise (advanced)</string>
    <string name="setup_elevation_only">Setup Elevation Only</string>
    <string name="setup_visible_sunrise_only">Setup Visible Sunrise Only</string>
    <string name="do_not_setup_either_uses_mishor_sea_level_sunrise_sunset_for_both_zmanim_and_sunrise">Do Not setup anything\n\n(Uses Mishor/Sea Level Sunrise and Sunset for both zmanim and Sunrise)</string>
    <string name="alternate_download_request">Press this button to download the visible sunrise table from the Chai Tables website:</string>
    <string name="intro">Welcome!\n\nThe goal of this app is to help you create your own zmanim calendar according to Rabbi Ovadiah Yosef Z\"tl as accurately as possible.\n\nThere are 2 options in order to setup the zmanim for your location.\n\nThe \"Setup your city!\" option will setup the calendar according to the way that the Ohr HaChaim calendar, in Israel, sets it\'s zmanim. Pressing the "Setup your city!" button will take you to a page that will ask you to choose your city/area. Once you choose your city, it will set the elevation data for your city and it will also download a table that lists the times for VISIBLE sunrise throughout the next 2 years from a website called ChaiTables.com. This table will automatically be updated each year if possible.\n\nThe \"Advanced Setup\" option allows you to choose whether you want to set the elevation data for your city, or download the visible sunrise tables, or to do neither one and use Mishor (Sea Level) sunrise.\n\nKnow that the elevation data changes for each and every city and you will need to set the elevation data of your city every time you change cities.</string>
    <string name="what_language_would_you_like_the_zmanim_to_be_in">What language would you like the zmanim to be in?</string>
    <string name="hebrew">Hebrew</string>
    <string name="english">English</string>
    <string name="setup">Setup</string>
    <string name="molad_calculator">Molad Calculator</string>
    <string name="moon_background">moon background</string>
    <string name="note_times_are_just_for_reference_you_should_ask_a_rav_if_you_can_say_the_bracha_earlier_or_later">Disclaimer: Times are just for reference, you should ask a rav if you can say the bracha earlier or later.</string>
    <string name="latest_birchat_halevanah_15_days">Latest Birchat Halevanah (15 days):</string>
    <string name="earliest_birchat_halevanah_7_days">Earliest Birchat Halevanah (7 days):</string>
    <string name="the_molad_for_this_month_in_your_timezone">The Molad for this month in your timezone:</string>
    <string name="change_date">Change Date</string>
    <string name="the_molad_time_announced">The molad time announced:</string>
    <string name="title_activity_shabbat">ShabbatActivity</string>
    <string name="dummy_button">Dummy Button</string>
    <string name="dummy_content">DUMMY\nCONTENT</string>
    <string name="shabbat_mode">Shabbat/Chag Mode</string>
    <string name="refresh">Refresh</string>
    <string name="full_restart">Full Restart</string>
    <string name="translated_english">Translated English</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="show_introduction">Show Introduction?</string>
    <string name="ohr_hachaim_nmode">Ohr HaChaim\nSetup</string>
    <string name="if_you_want_to_make_your_zmanim_like_the_ohr_hachaim_calendar_in_israel">If you want to make your zmanim like the Ohr HaChaim calendar in Israel, you can press on this button. Otherwise, you can choose the advanced setup to specify exactly what you want.</string>
    <string name="if_you_want_to_specify_what_to_setup">If you want to specify what to setup:</string>
    <string name="yalkut_yosef_quote">yalkut yosef quote</string>
    <string name="left">left</string>
    <string name="right">right</string>
    <string name="skip_for_now">Skip For Now?</string>
    <string name="or">OR</string>
    <string name="give_location_permission">Give Location Permission</string>
    <string name="please_select_a_method_to_find_your_location">Please select a method to find your location</string>
    <string name="simple_setup">Simple Setup</string>
    <string name="select_your_country">Select your country:</string>
    <string name="select_your_state">Select your state:</string>
    <string name="select_your_metro_area">Select your metro area:</string>
    <string name="chaitables_instructions">Please go to chaitables.com and create a table of the current year for the area you specified. Then copy the link/address of the table and enter it here:</string>
    <string name="go_to_the_website_in_the_app">Go to the website in the app</string>
    <string name="set_link">Set Link</string>
    <string name="table_link">Table link</string>
    <string name="skip">Skip?</string>
    <string name="geonames">GeoNames</string>
    <string name="area_not_listed">Area not listed?</string>
    <string name="setup_your_city">Setup your city!</string>
    <string name="title_activity_notification_settings">Notification Settings</string>
    <string name="min">min</string>
    <string name="weekly_view">Weekly View</string>
    <string name="website">Website</string>
    <string name="use_elevation">Use Elevation?</string>
    <string name="add_widget">Add widget</string>
    <string name="app_widget_description">This widget will show the current days most important zmanim</string>
    <string name="zmanim">Zmanim</string>
</resources>